arq.zafrani@gmail.com +50766759519

Panama, Panama 007099

Skills

- Design ideas
- Cost breakdowns
- Site appraisals
- Project management
- Group presentations
- Construction estimation
- Interior design
- Site planning and design expert
- Schematic design
- Site and environmental analysis
- Revit
- Project Planning
- Strong conceptual and schematic design skills
- In-depth knowledge of programming
- Land use planning
- Creative and artistic
- Community planning
- · Proficient in NewForma
- Performance improvements
- · Work flow planning
- Cost reduction and containment
- Multi-unit operations management
- Purchasing and procurement
- Risk management
- Account development and networking
- Contract negotiation expertise
- Presentations
- Baseline schedules creation
- Staff training and motivation
- Microsoft Office Suite expert
- Budget control

Abraham Zafrani

Summary

Dedicated Architect with more than 18 years of experience leading and collaborating Architect Designer / Project Manager on extensive technical designs. Presents in-depth technological knowledge to satisfy up-to-date guidelines for project roadmapping, launch and provisioning.

Offering excellent project management, multi-tasking and communication skills to coordinate multiple, concurrent projects with competing demands. Makes sound decisions in high-pressure settings and utilize analytical problem-solving skills to troubleshoot and resolve issues. Articulate communicator with strong customer service skills.

Organized and motivated employee eager to apply time management and organizational skills in various environments. Seeking entry-level opportunities to expand skills while facilitating company growth.

Experience

BRG Real Sate - Assistant Architect Panama , Panama 01/1998 - 11/2003

- Prepared project documents and reports.
- Supported senior architectural staff with clerical and administrative tasks.
- · Generated ideas as part of early stages of design processes.
- Assisted clients with being involved in design process with direct contact and support.
- Created blueprints using computer-aided design programs such as AutoCad.
- Administered contracts for architecture projects by reviewing contractor drawings and data.
- Put together and delivered project presentations to stakeholders.
- Assisted Senior and Executive Architects with preparing materials and documents for permitting process.

Holzer Architects & Assoc, - Design Assistant Panama, Panama 11/2003 - 10/2008

- Measured rooms and documented information to plan layouts.
- Ordered fabric and finish samples to view options in person.
- Researched fixtures and furnishings aligned with project requirements and design style.

- Productivity improvement
- Schedule management

Education And Training

11/2000
Bachelor Of Arts:
Architecture
Universidad De Panama
Panama City Panama

11/2021
Master Of Arts:
Architect Urban Space &
Mobility
Universidad International
De Valencia
Barcelona, Espana

07/2015 Curse of Ilumination Hubbel Lighting Chicago, United Sates

09/2012 Construction Materials Global Shop Europe Germany, Europe

09/2012 Interior Design Course Global Shop United States Chicago, United States

01/2009 Electric Design Intensive Seminary Bogota, Colombia

02/2014
Finishing And Furniture
Global Shop China
QUANZHOU MIKO FACTORY
CO.,LTD

05/2021 Digital Marketing Be Master Bogota Colombia

- Gathered price quotes from contractors and vendors.
- Created project cost estimates for client review and approval.
- Grouped finish selections and prepared professional design boards for client.
- Prepared and updated drawings such as blueprints and elevations using Cad.
- Carried out site visits to identify specifications.
- Used proven methods to craft and test design solutions that addressed real customer challenges.
- Consulted on tone, style and subject matter, driving layout and design.

H & Regency Group - Construction Manager Panama / Costa Rica , Panama / San Jose 12/2008 - 02/2013

- Monitored daily construction and evaluated project progress, contract compliance and safety.
- Resolved issues during construction and commissioning phases to maintain tight schedules and budget levels.
- Managed project operations, budget and timeline and collaborated with stakeholders to review status.
- Organized and participated in monthly on-site meetings with clientele and subcontractors.
- Coordinated construction planning, material resources and staff scheduling for 5-6 simultaneous jobs.
- Assessed and created construction budgets to facilitate approved projects within construction codes.
- Monitored job sites to analyze problems and recommend and implement solutions.
- Communicated safety standards to laborers and sub-contractors and enforced safety regulations on job sites.
- Planned, organized and managed crews and subcontractors through expert communication and handling of work orders and purchase orders.
- Established relationships with construction manager and contractors to align priorities, goals and objectives.

General Manager - Senior Architectural Designer / Project Manager

Panama / Colombia, Panama / Colombia 12/2013 - 12/2020

- Managed implementation of human-centered design approaches to standardize design methodologies.
- Hired team of service designers to develop smooth workflow through creation of procedures and guidelines.
- Conducted material tests to guarantee material would effectively meet design requirements.
- Maintained project schedules by managing deadlines and adjusting workflow
- · Maintained close connection with project personnel to quickly

09/2021

Analisis De Mercado Stocks Financial Zigma Finance Academy Bogota, Colombia

10/2013 Autocad & Revit Course Domestika Panama

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://www.linkedin.com /in/mindsarchitects/
- https://www.facebook.com /mindsarchitectsstudio/
- https://www.instagram.co m/mindsarchitectstudio /reels/

Certifications

- Certified Illumination Hubbell company ,May 2015.
- Certified Construction Materials Global shop Europe 2010
- Certified Interior Design Global Shop USA sep 2012
- Certified Constructions Materials Global Shop China may 2014
- Certified Electric Design workshop Feb 2013
- Certified Finished and interior color paint Global Shop Usa 2005

- identify and resolve problems.
- Identified, addressed and either resolved or escalated project issues.
- Assigned specific tasks to personnel, balancing scheduling demands, available resources and personal skill sets to achieve best possible project outcomes.
- Implemented change management processes when issues arose to keep project moving forward and adjust to shifted priorities.
- Managed submittals and processing of Requests for Information between general contractor, owner and owner's consultants.
- Visited locations to observe operations and determine opportunities to streamline processes and achieve cost reductions.
- Monitored design processes from conceptual phase through construction.
- Evaluated, determined and delegated tasks to staff based on client needs, capacity planning and project-specific initiatives.
- Monitored internal financial budgets to measure against projections.
- Completed thorough risk assessments and deployed management and response strategies to prevent roadblocks.
- Converted existing business objectives into specific measurable, time-based goals and realistic action plans.
- Created detailed report on strengths and weaknesses of current project management for client companies.
- Demonstrated and taught how to close out major, challenging projects without alienating customers or losing money on projects.
- Coached project management teams on recognizing and minimizing risks, using key actual projects as examples.

Accomplishments

- · Consistently maintained high customer satisfaction ratings.
- Created highly effective new program that significantly impacted efficiency and improved operations.
- Realize effort in ongoing effort to boost revenue while reducing costs.

Activities And Honors

Member, Small Business Association (2008 - present)